Okay, so let's discuss scope management
now.
Now scope management defines the
boundaries of the project.
It's basically defining what is included,
what is excluded.
This is what we're going to do,
this is what we're not going to do.
That's what we mean by boundaries.
So think of though there's constraints.
Scope will contain the constraints of your
project, right?
So it's basically making sure that you're
doing all the work necessary to complete
your project, and only the work necessary
to complete your project, right?
You're not doing anything additional,
right?
You are meeting the scope of the project,
you are meeting your customer's
requirements, and you're doing all of the
work necessary to meet those customers'
requirements.
You are doing all the
work necessary and only
the work necessary
to complete the project.
Okay.
Now, a couple of things
then that we are trying
to prevent, throughout this whole project.
We are trying to prevent scope creep and
goal plating.
So scope management then
is there to provide an entire
understanding what's to be
delivered, what is not to be delivered.
So we can avoid scope creep and goal
plating.
Now, let's talk about scope creep and goal
What do they mean?
Well, scope creep and goal plating both
refer to uncontrolled changes.
Right.
So scope creep, the official definition of
scope creep is, you know, what I have in
this first bullet point here, the
uncontrolled expansion of work while still
being held accountable to the original
time and budget.
All right.
So let's say customer comes along and
says, can you add in this functionality?
And you say, okay, well, that's scope
creep.
Scope creep is the uncontrolled expansion.
Right.
So customer comes
along, can you add in this
functionality and you just
add it in, that is scope creep.
If, on the other hand, you can push back
and you say, let's go through a change
control and you go through the whole
change control process and the change
control board approves it, now it's no
longer scope creep because as you're going
through the change control process,
you're doing an impact analysis,
right, seeing how much extra it's going to
cost, how long it's going to take.
And so now if it gets approved,
then now it's no longer.
longer scope creep
because now it's properly
controlled, it's properly approved, right?
So scope creep is always the uncontrolled
expansion while still being held
accountable to your original time and
budget.
So again, if the customer wants some
additional requirements and they agree to
pay for it and extend the timeline,
right, and we do the full impact analysis
and see, you know, what
other impacts is going to be
to resources and other
areas of the project, right?
And we go through the whole change control
process, everything gets approved, right?
The assumption is with
the approval then, that takes
into consideration the
budget and the timeline.
Now it's no longer scope creep.
And there's nothing wrong with having an
addition to scope, right?
As long as it's been properly controlled.
And that's the biggest thing about scope
creep, right, is it's uncontrolled.
As long as it is properly controlled,
then it is no longer scope creep.
Right.
Now, the difference between scope creep
and goal plating though, right,
scope creep is requested by the customer.
The customer is asking for some additional
requirements.
Whereas goal plating is actually done by
the team.
The team is giving freebies to the customer
that they didn't originally request.
Right, let's add in this little functionality,
customer's going to be really happy.
Well, if the customer didn't ask for it,
why are we adding it in?
Right, okay, they might be really happy,
but then these can have runaway costs.
Both scope creep and go plating can have
runaway costs.
Again, what we're trying to
do is we're basically trying to
do all the work necessary to
complete the project and only
the work necessary
to complete the project.
So we shouldn't be adding anything
additional.
Right.
And even by, you know, even if it's not
something that the customer is necessarily
going to be really happy about,
goal plating is still just adding
additional functionality that wasn't part
of the original scope of the project.
So, for example, in the IT world,
right, one of the developers adds in an
additional module, right, an
additional coding module to help
their coding being a lot
easier, make their coding easier.
Right.
So that's not impacting the customer.
the customer is not
going to really see that,
but that could impact
other areas of the project.
If we didn't do a proper impact analysis
of this module that the developer is
downloading, it's always important to do a
proper, full impact analysis.
So scope creep and goal plating is
something always to be avoided.
And it's scope management then,
right?
The whole idea of scope management,
managing your scope, right?
We want to collect our requirements from
the customer, understand what the customer
wants, what the customer needs,
understand what is to be delivered,
create the scope of the project, and
then stick to the scope of the project.
And then any changes, then, need to go
through a change control, right?
Now, how do we avoid scope creep and goal
plating?
Well, I just said that.
Go through a change control.
First of all, understand the scope of the
project.
Understand the requirements.
Understand what the customer wants,
what the customer doesn't want,
understand what is to be delivered,
right?
And that includes, not just about the
requirements of the customer, but all
requirements, including standards, right,
industry standards, regulations, right?
What regulations do we need to abide by,
right?
Are we abiding by ISO standards?
If we're building a house, right, we need
to abide by the building codes, right?
So all of that, that is all part of your
scope, all part of the
scope of the project.
Right.
So understanding that up front at the
beginning of the project and understanding
that throughout the project, effectively
communicating throughout the project and
then going through a proper change control
process.
And as I mentioned, addition
to scope is acceptable as
long as it is properly controlled
and properly approved.